Wesley Anderson

🗣 Springfield, MA, United States 🛮 🗷 wes@wesanderson.net 🥀 wesanderson.net



I am a software engineer with experience in JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, and various technologies. I am a co-creator of Chimera, which automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate synchronously on AWS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022 - present

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Chimera

Chimera (https://chimera-deploy.dev/ ☑) automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate synchronously on AWS. It reduces the risk of introducing bugs that propagate through your microservice infrastructure by gradually shifting traffic to the canary while automating canary analysis.

- Designed initial workflow diagrams
- Created a microservice infrastructure on AWS to test Chimera
- Implemented Chimera's ability to set up a CloudWatch agent that monitors metrics from the canary microservice
- Developed Chimera's ability to automate threshold analysis on the canary using metrics from CloudWatch
- Dockerized Chimera for simple execution in various environments
- Co-presented a live tech talk about Chimera
- Wrote documentation for setting up and installing Chimera within its repository
- Co-authored Chimera's technical case study

Technologies Used: React, NodeJS, Express, Docker, AWS

2020 - 2022

Software Engineer

- GitTix: An e-commerce app using microservices -- React, Next.js, Express, TypeScript, Mongo, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes
- Requesto: An RequestBin-like app -- NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, Mongo
- Reaction: A Trello-like app -- React, NodeJS, Express, Mongo

2016 - 2020

Researcher and Instructor of Philosophy & Logic, Various Institutes (including, Western New England University, Smith College, Konrad Lorenz Institute, and Arizona State University)

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021

Launch School, Software Engineering

Multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum emphasizing mastery of programming fundamentals and problem-solving -- launchschool.com/employers ☑

2011 - 2016

Ph.D. in History and Philosophy of Science, Arizona State University



Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Go

Technologies

Docker, Git/GitHub, CI/CD, Container Orchestration

Frameworks

Express, React, Next.js

Cloud

AWS: ECS, ECR, Fargate, App Mesh, CloudWatch, CloudFormation

DigitalOcean: Kubernetes, Droplet